<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Metadata on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/metadata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metadata on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/metadata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>oai - an OAI-PMH client</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/09/oai-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/09/oai-client/</guid>
      <description>oai is a general purpose client to work with any &amp;lsquo;OAI-PMH&amp;rsquo; service. The &amp;lsquo;OAI-PMH&amp;rsquo; protocol is described at https://www.openarchives.org/OAI/openarchivesprotocol.html. The main functions follow the OAI-PMH verbs:
GetRecord Identify ListIdentifiers ListMetadataFormats ListRecords ListSets The repo is at https://github.com/sckott/oai
I will be using this in a number of packages I maintain that use OAI-PMH data services. If you try it, let me know what you think.
This package is heading to rOpenSci soon: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>csl - an R client for Citation Style Language data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/03/csl-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/03/csl-client/</guid>
      <description>CSL (Citation Style Language) is used quite widely now to specify citations in a standard fashion. csl is an R client for exploring CSL styles, and is inspired by the Ruby gem csl. For example, csl is given back in the PLOS Lagotto article level metric API (follow https://alm.plos.org/api/v5/articles?ids=10.1371%252Fjournal.pone.0025110&amp;amp;info=detail&amp;amp;source_id=crossref).
Let me know if you have any feedback at the repo https://github.com/ropensci/csl
Install install.packages(&amp;#34;devtools&amp;#34;) devtools::install_github(&amp;#34;ropensci/csl&amp;#34;) library(&amp;#34;csl&amp;#34;) Load CSL style from a URL You can load CSL styles from either a URL or a local file on your machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scholarly metadata in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/r-metadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/03/r-metadata/</guid>
      <description>Scholarly metadata - the meta-information surrounding articles - can be super useful. Although metadata does not contain the full content of articles, it contains a lot of useful information, including title, authors, abstract, URL to the article, etc.
One of the largest sources of metadata is provided via the Open Archives Initiative Protocol for Metadata Harvesting or OAI-PMH. Many publishers, provide their metadata through their own endpoint, and implement the standard OAI-PMH methods: GetRecord, Identify, ListIdentifiers, ListMetadataFormats, ListRecords, and ListSets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scholarly metadata from R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/rmetadata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/rmetadata/</guid>
      <description>Metadata! Metadata is very cool. It&amp;rsquo;s super hot right now - everybody is talking about it. Okay, maybe not everyone, but it&amp;rsquo;s an important part of archiving scholarly work.
We are working on a repo on GitHub rmetadata to be a one stop shop for querying metadata from around the web. Various repos on GitHub we have started - rpmc, rdatacite, rdryad, rpensoft, rhindawi - will at least in part be folded into rmetadata.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
