<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Workflow on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/workflow/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Workflow on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/workflow/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Sublime Text workflow/setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2018/01/sublime-text-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2018/01/sublime-text-workflow/</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://www.sublimetext.com/">Sublime Text</a> is pretty great.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s start at the beginning.</p>
<p>Why would my primary editing tool not be vim? My background is as a biologist, spending way to many years in grad school. My first programming language was <a href="https://www.r-project.org/">R</a> back in 2006; my first text editor about the same year was <a href="https://notepad-plus-plus.org/">Notepad++</a>; my first interaction with the cli was probably a year later or so (but that was on Windows).</p>
<p>After using Notepad++ for a few years, I stumbled upon Sublime Text via advice from a friend. I used it for a few years without paying (which you can still do), and after that realized it was worth paying for. They now have an easy to use <a href="https://forum.sublimetext.com/">Discourse forum</a> too.</p>
<p>Anyway, vim is too intimidating to me, and at this point I like my workflow enough to not want to spend the time learning vim.</p>
<h2 id="why-sublime-text">Why Sublime Text?</h2>
<p>I have found Sublime Text to be faster than at least <a href="https://atom.io/">Atom</a>, ESPECIALLY when dealing with large files. Atom seems to get bogged down with a very large file and you can take a long time to scroll through it.</p>
<p>I like the idea of supporting the small team behind Sublime Text rather than the presumably large team behind Atom or the presumably extremely large team behind <a href="https://code.visualstudio.com/">vscode</a>.</p>
<p>Can&rsquo;t think of any other reasons - the speed one is enough reason :)</p>
<p>p.s. I&rsquo;ve never tried vscode.</p>
<h2 id="why-r-and-sublime-text">Why R and Sublime Text?</h2>
<p>RStudio has been great, and I still use it from time to time. However, it&rsquo;s started to be buggy here and there, and anyway, I do most everything else in Sublime Text so it doesn&rsquo;t take much to push me towards Sublime Text for every project I do. I definitely prefer RStudio when working on R packages that include C++ code as it helps me out a lot as a C++ newb.</p>
<p>The key thing that brought me over to using Sublime Text and R is being able to send code reliably to my cli of choice with a keyboard shortcut (see <code>SendCode</code> below).</p>
<p>I do development in other languages besides R - primarily Ruby and Python - so having a primary workflow that is agnostic with respect to the programming language is really nice.</p>
<h2 id="my-sublime-text-packages">My Sublime Text packages</h2>
<p>(check out SB packages at <a href="https://packagecontrol.io/">https://packagecontrol.io/</a>)</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://packagecontrol.io/packages/GitSavvy">GitSavvy</a>
<ul>
<li>lots of good Git goodies</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://packagecontrol.io/packages/MarkdownEditing">MarkdownEditing</a>
<ul>
<li>gotta have markdown support</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://packagecontrol.io/packages/R-Box">R-Box</a>
<ul>
<li>lots of R tools including building and installing packages</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://packagecontrol.io/packages/SendCode">SendCode</a>
<ul>
<li>crucial for using Sublime Text and R on the cli - sends code from Sublime Text to your cli of choice. I use <a href="https://www.iterm2.com/">iTerm2</a> as my cli.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://packagecontrol.io/packages/GotoWindow">GotoWindow</a>
<ul>
<li>speeds up your work a lot by quickly switching between projects with a keyboard shortcut</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/icio/sublime-text-marked">Marked integration</a>
<ul>
<li>Marked is a great markdown app - really nice to have an integration with Marked to quickly open it from Sublime</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="other-useful-things">Other useful things</h2>
<ul>
<li>Do make sure to enable <code>subl</code> - a shortcut cli command to open Sublime Text - see <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/questions/16199581/open-sublime-text-from-terminal-in-macos">https://stackoverflow.com/questions/16199581/open-sublime-text-from-terminal-in-macos</a> for discussion of how to do it. It&rsquo;s use case for me is opening up the current directory on your cli in Sublime Text.</li>
<li>Set Sublime Text as your default editor for git work, check out <a href="https://help.github.com/articles/associating-text-editors-with-git/">https://help.github.com/articles/associating-text-editors-with-git/</a> for guidance</li>
<li>Unrelated to Sublime Text, but if you go this route of separate text editor and cli, then arranging windows can start to slow you down a bit. On osx, there&rsquo;s a little app called <a href="https://www.spectacleapp.com/">Spectacle</a> that provides keyboard shortcuts for easily arranging windows in lots of combinations.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="the-setup">The setup</h2>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/2018-01-31-sublime-text-workflow/sbandr.png" alt=""  />
</p>
]]></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
