<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Text-Mining on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/text-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Text-Mining on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/text-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>text mining, apis, and parsing api logs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2019/03/apis-text-mining-logs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2019/03/apis-text-mining-logs/</guid>
      <description>Acquiring full text articles fulltext is an R package I maintain to obtain full text versions of research articles for text mining.
It&amp;rsquo;s a hard problem, with a spaghetti web of code. One of the hard problems is figuring out what the URL is for the full text version of an article. Publishers do not have consistent URL patterns through time, and so you can not set rules once and never revisit them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>nonoyes - text analysis of Reply All podcast transcripts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2016/08/no-no-yes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2016/08/no-no-yes/</guid>
      <description>Setup URLs Episode names Transcripts Summary word usage Sentiment Most common positive and negative words Reply All is a great podcast. I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to learn some text analysis tools, and transcripts from the podcast are on their site.
Took some approaches outlined in the tidytext package in this vignette, and used the tokenizers package, and some of the tidyverse.
Code on github at sckott/nonoyes
Also check out the html version</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>fulltext - a package to help you mine text</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/08/full-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/08/full-text/</guid>
      <description>Finally, we got fulltext up on CRAN - our first commit was May last year. fulltext is a package to facilitate text mining. It focuses on open access journals. This package makes it easier to search for articles, download those articles in full text if available, convert pdf format to plain text, and extract text chunks for vizualization/analysis. We are planning to add bits for analysis in future versions. We&amp;rsquo;ve been working on this package for a while now.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
