<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Taxonomic on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/taxonomic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Taxonomic on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/taxonomic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resolving species names when you have a lot of them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/tnrs-use-case/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/01/tnrs-use-case/</guid>
      <description>taxize use case: Resolving species names when you have a lot of them Species names can be a pain in the ass, especially if you are an ecologist. We ecologists aren&amp;rsquo;t trained in taxonomy, yet we often end up with huge species lists. Of course we want to correct any spelling errors in the names, and get the newest names for our species, resolve any synonyms, etc.
We are building tools into our R package taxize, that will let you check your species names to make sure they are correct.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hitting the Global Names Resolver API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/07/global-names-resolver/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/07/global-names-resolver/</guid>
      <description>Example of using the Global Names Resolver API to check species names There are a number of options for resolution of taxonomic names. The Taxonomic Name Resolution Service (TNRS) comes to mind. There is a new service for taxonomic name resoultion called the Global Names Resolver. They describe the service thusly &amp;ldquo;Resolve lists of scientific names against known sources. This service parses incoming names, executes exact or fuzzy matching as required, and displays a confidence score for each match along with its identifier.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
