<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Datasets on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/datasets/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Datasets on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/datasets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>oai - an OAI-PMH client</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/09/oai-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/09/oai-client/</guid>
      <description>oai is a general purpose client to work with any &amp;lsquo;OAI-PMH&amp;rsquo; service. The &amp;lsquo;OAI-PMH&amp;rsquo; protocol is described at https://www.openarchives.org/OAI/openarchivesprotocol.html. The main functions follow the OAI-PMH verbs:
GetRecord Identify ListIdentifiers ListMetadataFormats ListRecords ListSets The repo is at https://github.com/sckott/oai
I will be using this in a number of packages I maintain that use OAI-PMH data services. If you try it, let me know what you think.
This package is heading to rOpenSci soon: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weecology can has new mammal dataset</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/12/weecology-can-has-new-mammal-dataset/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 08:11:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/12/weecology-can-has-new-mammal-dataset/</guid>
      <description>So the Weecology folks have published a large dataset on mammal communities in a data paper in Ecology. I know nothing about mammal communities, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean one can&amp;rsquo;t play with the data&amp;hellip;
Their dataset consists of five csv files: communities, references, sites, species, and trapping data Where are these sites, and by the way, do they vary much in altitude? Let&amp;rsquo;s zoom in on just the states What phylogenies can we get for the species in this dataset?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My little presentation on getting web data through R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/my-little-presentation-on-getting-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 11:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/10/my-little-presentation-on-getting-web/</guid>
      <description> With examples from rOpenSci R packages.&amp;nbsp;p.s. I am no expert at this...
Web data from R View more presentations from schamber </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rnpn: An R interface for the National Phenology Network</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/rnpn-r-interface-for-national-phenology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 10:26:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/rnpn-r-interface-for-national-phenology/</guid>
      <description>The team at rOpenSci and I have been working on a wrapper for the USA National Phenology Network API. The following is a demo of some of the current possibilities. We will have more functions down the road. Get the publicly available code, and contribute, at Github here. If you try this out look at the Description file for the required R packages to run rnpn. Let us know at Github (here) or at our website http://ropensci.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(#ESA11) rOpenSci: a collaborative effort to develop R-based tools for facilitating Open Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/esa11-ropensci-collaborative-effort-to_08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 10:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/esa11-ropensci-collaborative-effort-to_08/</guid>
      <description>Our development team would like to announce the launch of rOpenSci. As the title states, this project aims to create R packages to make open science more available to researchers.
http://ropensci.org/
What this means is that we seek to connect researchers using R with as much open data as possible, mainly through APIs. There are a number of R packages that already do this (e.g., infochimps, twitteR), but we are making more packages, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archiving ecology/evolution data sets online</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/archiving-ecologyevolution-data-sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 21:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/archiving-ecologyevolution-data-sets/</guid>
      <description>We now have many options for archiving data sets online:
Dryad, KNB, Ecological Archives, Ecology Data Papers, Ecological Data, etc.
However, these portals largely do not communicate with one another as far as I know, and there is no way to search over all data set sources, again, as far as I know. So, I wonder if it would ease finding of all these different data sets to get these different sites to get their data sets cloned on a site like Infochimps, or have links from Infochimps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>rbold: An R Interface for Bold Systems barcode repository</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/rbold-an-r-interface-for-bold-systems-barcode-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2011 09:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/rbold-an-r-interface-for-bold-systems-barcode-repository/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wanted to search and fetch barcode data from Bold Systems?
I am developing functions to interface with Bold from R. I just started, but hopefully folks will find it useful.
The code is at Github here. The two functions are still very buggy, so please bring up issues below, or in the Issues area on Github. For example, some searches work and other similar searches don&amp;rsquo;t. Apologies in advance for the bugs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iEvoBio 2011 Synopsis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>We just wrapped up the 2011 iEvoBio meeting. It was awesome! If you didn&amp;rsquo;t go this year or last year, definitely think about going next year.
Here is a list of the cool projects that were discussed at the meeting (apologies if I left some out):
Vistrails: workflow tool, awesome project by Claudio Silva Commplish: purpose is to use via API&amp;rsquo;s, not with the web UI Phylopic: a database of life-form silouhettes, including an API for remote access, sweet!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenStates from R via API: watch your elected representatives</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/openstates-from-r-via-api-watch-your-elected-representatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2011 23:19:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/openstates-from-r-via-api-watch-your-elected-representatives/</guid>
      <description>I am writing some functions to acquire data from the OpenStates project, via their API. They have a great support community at Google Groups as well.
On its face this post is not obviously about ecology or evolution, but well, our elected representatives do, so to speak, hold our environment in a noose, ready to let the Earth hang any day.
Code I am developing is over at Github. Here is an example of its use in R, in this case using the Bill Search option (billsearch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Farmer&#39;s markets data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/02/farmer-s-markets-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 22:41:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/02/farmer-s-markets-data/</guid>
      <description>I combined USDA data on farmer&amp;rsquo;s markets in the US with population census data to get an idea of the disparity in farmers markets by state, and then also expressed per capita.
Download USDA data here. The formatted file I used below is here (in excel format, although I read into R as csv file). The census data is read from url as below.
California has a ton of absolute number of farmer&amp;rsquo;s markets, but Vermont takes the cake by far with number of markets per capita.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
