<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Openaccess on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/openaccess/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Openaccess on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 12:28:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/openaccess/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>rOpenSci won 3rd place in the PLoS-Mendeley Binary Battle!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/ropensci-won-3rd-place-in-the-plos-mendeley-binary-battle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2011 12:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/ropensci-won-3rd-place-in-the-plos-mendeley-binary-battle/</guid>
      <description>I am part of the rOpenSci development team (along with Carl Boettiger, Karthik Ram, and Nick Fabina).
Our website: http://ropensci.org/.
Code at Github: https://github.com/ropensci
We entered two of our R packages for integrating with PLoS Journals (rplos) and Mendeley (RMendeley) in the Mendeley-PLoS Binary Battle. Get them at GitHub (rplos; RMendeley). These two packages allow users (from R! of course) to search and retrieve data from PLoS journals (including their altmetrics data), and from Mendeley.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ten Simple Rules for OA Publishers talk by Philip Bourne</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/ten-simple-rules-for-oa-publishers-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2011 14:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/ten-simple-rules-for-oa-publishers-talk/</guid>
      <description> Ten Simple Rules for Open Access Publishers View more presentations from Philip Bourne </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>@drewconway interview on @DataNoBorders at the Strata conference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/drewconway-interview-on-datanoborders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 23:10:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/drewconway-interview-on-datanoborders/</guid>
      <description>The O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media Strata Summit has many interviews on YouTube (just search YouTube for it)Drew Conway is the author of a R packages, including infochimps, an R wrapper to the Infochimps API service.
The YouTube video:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open science talk by Carl Boettiger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/open-science-talk-by-carl-boettiger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2011 22:55:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/open-science-talk-by-carl-boettiger/</guid>
      <description>Carl Boettiger gave a talk on the topic of open science to incoming UC Davis graduate students.
Here is the audio click here
Here are the slides clickhere</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My take on an R introduction talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/my-take-on-r-introduction-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 13:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/my-take-on-r-introduction-talk/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: I put in an R tutorial as a Github gist below.
Here is a short intro R talk I gave today&amp;hellip;for what it&amp;rsquo;s worth&amp;hellip;
R Introduction View more presentations from schamber Here&amp;rsquo;s the tutorial in a GitHub gist: https://gist.github.com/1208321</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FigShare Talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/figshare-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2011 23:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/figshare-talk/</guid>
      <description>FigShare - I very much like this idea of a place to put your data online that is NOT published. Dryad is a nice place for datastes linked with published papers, but there isn&amp;rsquo;t really a place for datasets that perhaps did not make the cut for a published paper, and if known to the scientific community, could potentially help resolve the &amp;ldquo;file-drawer&amp;rdquo; effect in meta-analyses. (wow, run on sentence)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday at #ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/wednesday-at-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/wednesday-at-esa11/</guid>
      <description>Interesting talks/posters:
Ethan White&amp;rsquo;s poster describing EcologicalData.org was of course awesome given my interest in getting data into the hands of ecologists over at rOpenSci.org. Ethan also has software you can download on your machine to get the datasets you want easily - EcoData Retriever. [rOpenSci will try to take advantage of their work and allow you to call the retriever from R] Carl Boettiger&amp;rsquo;s talk was awesome. He explained how we need better tools to be able to predict collapses using early warning signals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monday at ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/monday-at-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 22:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/monday-at-esa11/</guid>
      <description>Monday was a good day at ESA in Austin. There were a few topics I promised to report on in my blogging/tweeting.
&amp;hellip;focused on open source data. Carly Strasser&amp;rsquo;s presentation on guidelines for data management was awesome (including other talks in the symposium on Creating Effective Data Management Plans for Ecological Research). Although this was a good session, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wish that they had hammered home the need for open science more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(#ESA11) rOpenSci: a collaborative effort to develop R-based tools for facilitating Open Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/esa11-ropensci-collaborative-effort-to_08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 10:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/esa11-ropensci-collaborative-effort-to_08/</guid>
      <description>Our development team would like to announce the launch of rOpenSci. As the title states, this project aims to create R packages to make open science more available to researchers.
http://ropensci.org/
What this means is that we seek to connect researchers using R with as much open data as possible, mainly through APIs. There are a number of R packages that already do this (e.g., infochimps, twitteR), but we are making more packages, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging/tweeting from ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/bloggingtweeting-from-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 14:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/bloggingtweeting-from-esa11/</guid>
      <description>I will be blogging about the upcoming Ecological Society of America meeting in Austin, TX. I will focus on discussing talks/posters that:
Have taken a cool approach to using data, or Have focused on open science/data, or Done something cool with R software, or Are just exciting in general I will also tweet throughout the meeting from @recology_ (yes the underscore is part of the name, recology was already taken). The hashtag for the meeting this year is #ESA11</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
