<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/cloud/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cloud on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>analogsea - an R client for the Digital Ocean API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2015/10/analogsea-cran/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2015/10/analogsea-cran/</guid>
      <description>analogsea is now on CRAN. We started developing the pkg back in May 2014, but just now getting the first version on CRAN. It&amp;rsquo;s a collaboration with Hadley and Winston Chang.
Most of analogsea package is for interacting with the Digital Ocean API, including:
Manage domains Manage ssh keys Get actions Manage images Manage droplets (servers) A number of convenience functions are included for doing tasks (e.g., resizing a droplet) that aren&amp;rsquo;t supported by Digital Ocean&amp;rsquo;s API out of the box (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>analogsea - v0.1 notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/06/analogsea-v01/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/06/analogsea-v01/</guid>
      <description>My last blog post introduced the R package I&amp;rsquo;m working on analogsea, an R client for the Digital Ocean API.
Things have changed a bit, including fillig out more functions for all API endpoints, and incorparting feedback from Hadley and Karthik. The package is as v0.1 now, so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d say a few things about how it works.
Note that Digital Ocean&amp;rsquo;s v2 API is in beta stage now, so the current version of analogsea at v0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>analogsea - an R client for the Digital Ocean API</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/analogsea/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/05/analogsea/</guid>
      <description>I think this package name is my best yet. Maybe it doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense though? At least it did at the time&amp;hellip;
Anyway, the main motivation for this package was to be able to automate spinning up Linux boxes to do cloud R/RStudio work. Of course if you are a command line native this is all easy for you, but if you are afraid of the command line and/or just don&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with it, this tool will hopefully help.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
