<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Sliced Software - PGnJ</title>
    <link>http://www.slicedsoftware.com</link>
    <description>PGnJ Software Updates</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>©2005-2009 Sliced Software, Inc.</copyright>
    <item>
      <title>1.1</title>
      <pubDate>Thu Aug 06 2009 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>tom@slicedsoftware.com</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      <div style="background-color:#FFFFCC;margin:2px 0 5px 0;padding:5px;">PGnJ is again free and it will stay that way.</div>
				<span style="font-size:larger;font-weight:bold;">Changes in 1.1</span><br>
				<br>
				<span style="font-weight:bold">Additions:</span>
      	<ul style="list-style-image:url(http://www.slicedsoftware.com/images/bullet.gif);margin-left:15px;">
      		<li>The registration system has been removed. PGnJ is again free and will remain that way.</li>
      		<li>QuickJoin has been added to the DataBrowser (double click a table) - Easily select any fields from a joined table and they will magically appear alongside their foreign key field in the data browser (PostgreSQL and MySQL supported).</li>
      		<li>Use the data browser to edit records directory, just double click to edit a field (PostgreSQL and MySQL supported).</li>
      	</ul>
      	<br>
      	<span style="font-weight:bold">Fixes:</span>
      	<ul style="list-style-image:url(http://www.slicedsoftware.com/images/bullet.gif);margin-left:15px;">
      		<li>Fixes an issue with OS X Java Update 4 (the application must be run in 32 bit mode)</li>
      	</ul>
      ]]></description>
      <link></link>
      <enclosure url="http://www.slicedsoftware.com/programs/pgnj/download?silent=true" length="7574535" type="application/zip"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1.0</title>
      <pubDate>Tue Nov 25 2008 23:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>tom@slicedsoftware.com</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
				<div style="background-color:#FFFFCC;margin:2px 0 5px 0;padding:5px;">This update brings over 40 new features and enhancements to PGnJ. Check out PGnJ 1.0 for free for 15 days! Mac OS X 10.4 or 10.5 required.</div>
				<span style="font-size:larger;font-weight:bold;">Changes in 1.0</span><br>
				<br>
				<span style="font-weight:bold">Additions:</span>
      	<ul style="list-style-image:url(http://www.slicedsoftware.com/images/bullet.gif);margin-left:15px;">
      		<li>Oracle support added. (Thanks, Lorgio!)</li>
			<li>SQLite support added. (Thanks, Milan!)</li>
			<li>Tab completion support for table and column names added to the query editor.</li>
			<li>A Script Library for managing SQL scripts added (:variables supported).</li>
			<li>A template system for generating DDL SQL templates.</li>
			<li>A common toolbar has been added to the Query Editor and Script Library views.</li>
			<li>A filter bar (CMD+F to focus) to filter and order data with SQL added in the DataBrowser. (Thanks, Lorgio!)</li>
			<li>The bookmark manager can now remember connection passwords.</li>
			<li>The execution engine has been completely rebuilt from scratch to better handle multiple queries regardless of type.</li>
			<li>The database tree now automatically refreshes when DDL is detected.</li>
			<li>The database tree's state is now recalled when the database is refreshed (expanded nodes remain expanded, selected node remains selected).</li>
			<li>SQL can now be executed directly from a file without first loading it into the query editor (for larger scripts).</li>
			<li>It is now possible to drop one more files directly onto the query editor's input area to load sql.</li>
			<li>Right clicking on a result set now reveals a pop-up menu that allows copying the content of either a single cell or the entire row in CSV format to the clipboard.</li>
			<li>The bookmark manager now remembers the last selected database type to ease the task of adding bookmarks.</li>
			<li>Table details are now pre-fetched in a background thread after connection to database is established.</li>
			<li>A drag handle has been added to the bottom left action bar to make resizing the sidebar easier.</li>
			<li>PGnJ can now remain running without any windows open (like standard Cocoa applications).</li>
			<li>Experimental horizontal scroll wheel support added (use preference to toggle).</li>
			<li>Added preference to convert all zero datetimes in MySQL to NULL (on by default; off causes exception).</li>
			<li>Added menu items and keyboard shortcuts to navigate the table details at the bottom of the sidebar.</li>
			<li>A shortcut (CMD+T) to focus on the database tree in the sidebar has been added.</li>
			<li>A shortcut (CMD+W) to close the preferences window when it is visible has been added.</li>
			<li>When started, PGnJ now specifically asks if it's okay to check for updates rather than defaulting to autochecking.</li>
      	</ul>
      	<br>
      	<span style="font-weight:bold">Changes:</span>
      	<ul style="list-style-image:url(http://www.slicedsoftware.com/images/bullet.gif);margin-left:15px;">
			<li>CSV Export no longer wraps integers, floats and booleans in quotes.</li>
			<li>The connection sheet and bookmark manager are now fully keyboard navigable.</li>
			<li>The connection sheet now cancels on escape. (Thanks, Manton!)</li>
			<li>The keyboard shortcut CMD+E and menu item 'Database > Execute SQL' now executes SQL when the QueryEditor is visible and reloads the DataBrowser when the DataBrowser is visible.</li>
			<li>Altered the row selection behavior on the database tree so that clicking on an expand/collapse arrow doesn't highlight that row unless the currently selected row is a child of that row.</li>
			<li>When using CMD-UP/CMD-DOWN quick history from the Query Editor, if there is SQL currently in the Editor, it is added to the history so that it isn't lost.</li>
			<li>The history browser (CMD-SHIFT-H) no longer automatically executes a SQL statement after selecting it and appropriately cleans up the query editor before loading the selected SQL.</li>
			<li>Connection sheets are now correctly document modal. (Thanks to Werner, the Quaqua developer!)</li>
			<li>Menu items are now properly enabled or disabled based on the context of the application.</li>
			<li>Where necessary, tooltips are assigned to disabled menu items to explain how they can be enabled.</li>
			<li>All tables are now borderless to be more in line with current trends in OS X application design.</li>
			<li>The background color of the sidebar has been darkened slightly to better resemble the sidebar background colors of other OS X applications.</li>
			<li>Polished dialogs with more appropriate copy and icons.</li>
			<li>The QueryEditor now receives focus upon a successful connection to a bookmark.</li>
			<li>When resizing the window, the sidebar now only grows the area containing the database tree rather than the table details section at the bottom.</li>
			<li>Updated Quaqua LAF to version 5.0.1. (Thanks to Werner, the Quaqua developer!)</li>
      	</ul>
      	<br>
      	<span style="font-weight:bold">Fixes:</span>
      	<ul style="list-style-image:url(http://www.slicedsoftware.com/images/bullet.gif);margin-left:15px;">
      		<li>Now able to issue ALTER, CREATE and DROP statements to MySQL databases.</li>
			<li>When a new bookmark is setup to connect to, it is now only added if the connection is successful.</li>
			<li>The AutoCheckForUpdates preference is no longer (accidently) ignored.</li>
			<li>Style changes in the query editor are no longer registered in the undo/redo history.</li>
			<li>When loading a sql file, the QueryEditor properly replaces the current view.</li>
			<li>Dialogs (sheets) now correctly gain focus, enabling keyboard interaction. (Thanks to Werner, the Quaqua developer!)</li>
			<li>Columns of a table no longer sporadically appear multiple times in the table details area.</li>
      	</ul>
      ]]></description>
      <link></link>
      <enclosure url="http://www.slicedsoftware.com/programs/pgnj/download?silent=true" length="6068417" type="application/zip"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>0.8</title>
      <pubDate>Sat Sep 01 2007 20:00:13 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>tsmango@gmail.com</author>
      <description><![CDATA[
      	<span style="font-size:larger;font-weight:bold;">Changes in 0.8</span><br>
      	<br>
      	<span style="font-weight:bold">Additions:</span>
      	<ul style="list-style-image:url(http://www.slicedsoftware.com/images/bullet.gif);margin-left:15px;">
      		<li>Added automatic Software Update System.</li>
      		<li>Added preference system and Preferences window.</li>
			<li>Added length of varchar to default view in column inspector. (Thanks, Lorgio!)</li>
			<li>Added ability to only execute certain SQL in Query Editor by simply highlighting what to execute. (Thanks, Daniel!)</li>
			<li>Added preference to automatically select the last connected bookmark when the connection sheet is opened (on by default).</li>
			<li>Added preference to automatically re-sizing columns to fit data (on by default - which is what PGnJ has done since version 0.5).</li>
			<li>Added preference to display &lt;null&gt; in results table when value is NULL in database (on by default).</li>
			<li>Added preference to remember window size and position (off by default).</li>
			<li>Added a real About box (Choose 'About PGnJ' from the Application menu).</li>
      	</ul>
      	<br>
      	<span style="font-weight:bold">Changes:</span>
      	<ul style="list-style-image:url(http://www.slicedsoftware.com/images/bullet.gif);margin-left:15px;">
			<li>Brought back keyboard focus support. Cycle from database tree to query editor to results table or database tree to right side to database tree with cmd-tab.</li>
			<li>Removed Java 5 specific language syntax to bring back support for versions of OS X lower than 10.4.</li>
			<li>Default window positions are now placed 100 pixels higher than dead center. About and Preference windows are 200 pixles above dead center.</li>
			<li>Replaced round aqua buttons on connection and bookmark manager sheets with placard style buttons.</li>
      	</ul>
      	<br>
      	<span style="font-weight:bold">Fixes:</span>
      	<ul style="list-style-image:url(http://www.slicedsoftware.com/images/bullet.gif);margin-left:15px;">
      		<li>Updated Quaqua LAF to version 3.9.1 to help fix a crash when attempting to make a new database connection.</li>
			<li>Corrected the behavior when left or right clicking on the database tree. (Thanks, Lorgio!)</li>
			<li>Corrected spelling of the word 'default' when showing more column details. (Thanks, H. Lally Singh!)</li>
			<li>Corrected a focus issue when starting the application which caused a slight UI blemish.</li>
			<li>Corrected various UI blemishes by restricting what components are focusable.</li>
			<li>Ensured that cells in the column detail tables remain uneditable.</li>
			<li>Removed inactive 'Find' from edit menu.</li>
			<li>Removed inactive 'Hide Table Inspector' from view menu.</li>
      	</ul>
      ]]></description>
      <link></link>
      <enclosure url="http://www.slicedsoftware.com/files/PGnJ/PGnJ_0.8.dmg.zip" length="2915752" type="application/zip"/>
    </item>
   </channel>
 </rss>