<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetings on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/meetings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetings on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/meetings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Altecology, a call to unconference action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/11/altecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/11/altecology/</guid>
      <description>Note: This post is cross-posted on Sandra Chung&amp;rsquo;s blog here.
The rise of the unconference The Ecological Society of America meeting is holding its 98th annual meeting next year in Minneapolis, MN. Several thousand students and professionals in ecological science and education will gather to hear and read the latest work and ideas in ecology in the familiar poster and lecture formats that are the core of every major scientific conference.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thursday at #ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/thursday-at-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 08:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/thursday-at-esa11/</guid>
      <description>Interesting talks/posters:
Richard Lankau presented research on trade-offs and competitive ability. He suggests that during range expansion selection for increased intraspecific competitive ability in older populations leads to loss of traits for interspecific competitive traits due to trade-offs between these traits.
Ellner emphatically states that rapid evolution DOES matter for ecological responses, and longer-term evolutionary patterns as well. [His paper on the talk he was giving came out prior to his talk, which he pointed out, good form sir]</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday at #ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/wednesday-at-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/wednesday-at-esa11/</guid>
      <description>Interesting talks/posters:
Ethan White&amp;rsquo;s poster describing EcologicalData.org was of course awesome given my interest in getting data into the hands of ecologists over at rOpenSci.org. Ethan also has software you can download on your machine to get the datasets you want easily - EcoData Retriever. [rOpenSci will try to take advantage of their work and allow you to call the retriever from R] Carl Boettiger&amp;rsquo;s talk was awesome. He explained how we need better tools to be able to predict collapses using early warning signals.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monday at ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/monday-at-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 22:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/monday-at-esa11/</guid>
      <description>Monday was a good day at ESA in Austin. There were a few topics I promised to report on in my blogging/tweeting.
&amp;hellip;focused on open source data. Carly Strasser&amp;rsquo;s presentation on guidelines for data management was awesome (including other talks in the symposium on Creating Effective Data Management Plans for Ecological Research). Although this was a good session, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wish that they had hammered home the need for open science more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging/tweeting from ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/bloggingtweeting-from-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 14:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/bloggingtweeting-from-esa11/</guid>
      <description>I will be blogging about the upcoming Ecological Society of America meeting in Austin, TX. I will focus on discussing talks/posters that:
Have taken a cool approach to using data, or Have focused on open science/data, or Done something cool with R software, or Are just exciting in general I will also tweet throughout the meeting from @recology_ (yes the underscore is part of the name, recology was already taken). The hashtag for the meeting this year is #ESA11</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Models in Evolutionary Ecology seminar, organized by Timothee Poisot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/models-in-evolutionary-ecology-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 07:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/models-in-evolutionary-ecology-seminar/</guid>
      <description>Here is one of the talks by Thomas Brouquet, and see the rest here.
Thomas Broquet by mez_en_video </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iEvoBio 2011 Synopsis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>We just wrapped up the 2011 iEvoBio meeting. It was awesome! If you didn&amp;rsquo;t go this year or last year, definitely think about going next year.
Here is a list of the cool projects that were discussed at the meeting (apologies if I left some out):
Vistrails: workflow tool, awesome project by Claudio Silva Commplish: purpose is to use via API&amp;rsquo;s, not with the web UI Phylopic: a database of life-form silouhettes, including an API for remote access, sweet!</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
