<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Meetings on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/meetings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meetings on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.143.1</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/meetings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Altecology, a call to unconference action</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/11/altecology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/11/altecology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Note: This post is cross-posted on Sandra Chung&amp;rsquo;s blog &lt;a href=&#34;http://sandrachung.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-rise-of-the-unconference&#34;&gt;The rise of the unconference&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ecological Society of America meeting is holding its &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.esa.org/minneapolis/&#34;&gt;98th annual meeting&lt;/a&gt; next year in Minneapolis, MN. Several thousand students and professionals in ecological science and education will gather to hear and read the latest work and ideas in ecology in the familiar poster and lecture formats that are the core of every major scientific conference. But a subset of these people will get a taste of something a little bit different: an unconference within the conference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Note: This post is cross-posted on Sandra Chung&rsquo;s blog <a href="http://sandrachung.com/">here</a>.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="the-rise-of-the-unconference">The rise of the unconference</h3>
<p>The Ecological Society of America meeting is holding its <a href="http://www.esa.org/minneapolis/">98th annual meeting</a> next year in Minneapolis, MN. Several thousand students and professionals in ecological science and education will gather to hear and read the latest work and ideas in ecology in the familiar poster and lecture formats that are the core of every major scientific conference. But a subset of these people will get a taste of something a little bit different: an unconference within the conference.</p>
<p>The most important difference between traditional science conferences and the unconference format is that it prioritizes human interaction. Often the best and most important parts of science meetings are the interactions between talks, next to posters, and at the end of the day over drinks. These connections pave the way for collaborations and friendships that nourish our professional and personal lives with shared opportunities, camaraderie and support.</p>
<p>In recognition of the increasing relative importance of the “meeting” part of a science meeting, the unconference format emphasizes interaction over presentation. It attempts to engage participants to the maximum extent reasonable in discussion and doing. <a href="http://scienceonline.com/">Science Online</a> is a good example of this unconference format, in which the session topics are typically decided on democratically by the conference attendees (partly before arrival, partly on arrival), and you vote with your feet by going to and leaving sessions as you desire.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="ecology-is-changing">Ecology is changing</h3>
<p>Ecology is now adopting some of the same online and social tools that are already accelerating innovation in computing and other science disciplines. Ecologists, ecology students and educators are asking many of the same basic questions they have always asked: What should we be doing? How do we do it better and faster? Social media, open source software, open science, altmetrics, crowdsourcing, crowdfunding, data visualization, data sharing, alternative peer review, and an increasing emphasis on more and better communication and collaboration are just some of the newer tools being put forth to help address those questions in the 21st century.</p>
<p>Social media is rapidly becoming more common in ecologists’ toolkits to disseminate news of their new papers, communicate about research and research tools, and even filter the deluge of publications. Tools like blogs, Twitter and Facebook are filling the communication gaps between annual meetings and adding a new layer of conversation and connection to conferences and classrooms.</p>
<p>Social media, in turn, is connecting scientists directly to people besides their immediate colleagues who appreciate the impact of their work and want it to continue. The crowdfunding movement - exemplified by Kickstarter - has spurred similar alternative science funding projects such as SciFund. #SciFund project has shown that social media engagement increases donations to crowdfunded research (<a href="http://jecology.libsyn.com/interview-with-jarrett-byrnes-on-science-crowdfunding">interview with Jarrett Byrnes</a>).</p>
<p>In addition, we are in the era of big data, and <a href="http://www.neoninc.org/news/big-data-part-i">this includes ecology</a>. To deal with this “data deluge”, ecologists increasingly want to learn how to manage, share, retrieve, use, and visualize data. There are new tools for all of these tasks - we need to aid each other in learning them. Online and offline communities are coalescing around the development and dissemination of these tools for the benefit of ecological science, and they are meeting face-to-face at our ecological unconference.</p>
<p>Science in general is becoming increasingly complex and calling for larger and larger collaborations. This growth in turn is spurring a drive toward more openness and transparency within the culture of science. The more collaborative and complex scientific study becomes, the more scientists depend upon each other to do good work that we can all build upon with confidence. The often unstated assumption about ecology, and all of science, is that research findings are reproducible; but that assumption is quite shaky given the increasing number of retractions (see the <a href="http://retractionwatch.wordpress.com/">Retraction Watch blog</a>) and findings that much research is not reproducible (see media coverage <a href="http://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v483/n7391/full/483531a.html">here</a> and <a href="http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/03/28/us-science-cancer-idUSBRE82R12P20120328">here</a>).</p>
<p>A recent initiative seeks to facilitate attempts to reproduce research: <a href="https://www.scienceexchange.com/reproducibility">The Reproducibility Initiative</a>. Jarrett Byrnes <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/JarrettByrnes/taking-the-ecological-conversation-online">spoke at #ESA2012</a> of how transparent, online discourse enhances our ability to discuss and improve our work and the work of our peers, both before and after publication.</p>
<p>Much of the ecological science community shares one or both of these goals: to do the best possible science, and to do it in a way that is most useful and accessible to colleagues and to society at large. The goal of this year’s ecological unconference is to introduce as many people as possible to resources - both tools and people - that can help all of us achieve those goals, on our own, or together.</p>
<p>One way we as ecologists can quickly make our research more reproducible is the way we write. By simply using tools that make reproducing what we have done easy to do, we can avoid retracted papers, failed drugs, and ruined careers.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="what-are-you-proposing">What are you proposing?</h3>
<p>We originally thought about a separate event from ESA itself, modeled after <a href="http://scienceonline.com/">Science Online</a>, incorporating a variety of topics. However, we thought testing the waters for this sort of non-traditional unconference format would be better in 2013. We are gathering ideas from the community (see “How do I make my voice heard?” below). The ideas on the wiki that get the most traction, and have 1-2 champions that are willing to see the idea through and lead the workshop at ESA will be turned in to proposals for ESA workshops. In addition, we will be submitting a proposal for an Ignite session at ESA. To summarise, we will be running:</p>
<ul>
<li>A few workshops (at lunch hours, and half-day). Topics may include:
<ul>
<li>Data sharing</li>
<li>Data visualization</li>
<li>Data management</li>
<li>Alternatives to academia</li>
<li>Blogging</li>
<li>Social media</li>
<li>Reproducible science writing</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>One Ignite session on “Tools for better/faster science”. See more about Ignite sessions <a href="http://www.esa.org/minneapolis/ignite.php">here</a>.</li>
<li>A “tweetup” event to socialize in a more relaxed atmosphere</li>
</ul>
<p>These will all be loosely aggregated under the <a href="https://twitter.com/search/realtime?q=%23AltEcology">#AltEcology</a> hashtag.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="how-do-i-make-my-voice-heard">How do I make my voice heard?</h3>
<p>We have set up a wiki in which anyone can contribute. Please share your ideas and voice your support for existing ones at the wiki <a href="http://ecologyunconference.wikispaces.com/">here</a>.  You can just throw ideas out there, or even propose new workshops and nominate people to lead them. We’re currently moving to transform existing ideas into ESA workshop and Ignite proposals to meet the <a href="http://www.esa.org/minneapolis/workshop.php">November 29 deadline</a>, but we’ll be incorporating input from the wiki right up to the meeting itself in August 2013.</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="get-in-touch">Get in touch</h3>
<p>If you have any questions/comments, let us know in the comments section below, tweet us (Sandra: <a href="https://twitter.com/sandramchung">@sandramchung</a>, Scott: <a href="https://twitter.com/recology_">@recology_</a>), or email (<a href="mailto:sandra.m.chung@gmail.com">Sandra</a>, <a href="mailto:myrmecocystus@gmail.com">Scott</a>).</p>
<hr>
<p>Get the .md file used to create this post <a href="https://github.com/sckott/sckott.github.com/tree/master/_posts/2012-11-15-altecology.md">at my github account</a>.  Written in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a>, with help from <a href="http://yihui.name/knitr/">knitr</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thursday at #ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/thursday-at-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2011 08:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/thursday-at-esa11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting talks/posters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Lankau presented research on trade-offs and competitive ability. He suggests that during range expansion selection for increased intraspecific competitive ability in older populations leads to loss of traits for interspecific competitive traits due to trade-offs between these traits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ellner emphatically states that rapid evolution DOES matter for ecological responses, and longer-term evolutionary patterns as well. [His paper on the talk he was giving came out prior to his talk, which he pointed out, good form sir]&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Interesting talks/posters:</p>
<p>Richard Lankau presented research on trade-offs and competitive ability. He suggests that during range expansion selection for increased intraspecific competitive ability in older populations leads to loss of traits for interspecific competitive traits due to trade-offs between these traits.</p>
<p>Ellner emphatically states that rapid evolution DOES matter for ecological responses, and longer-term evolutionary patterns as well. [His paper on the talk he was giving came out prior to his talk, which he pointed out, good form sir]</p>
<p>Lauren Sullivan gave an interesting talk on bottom up and top down effects on plant reproduction in one site of a huge network of sites doing similar nutrient and herbivory manipulations around the globe - NutNet (go here: <a href="http://nutnet.science.oregonstate.edu/">http://nutnet.science.oregonstate.edu/</a>).</p>
<p>Laura Prugh shows in California that the engineering effects (i.e., the mounds that they make) of giant kangaroo rats are more important for the associated food web than the species interaction effects (the proxy used was just density of rats).</p>
<p>Kristy Deiner suggests that chironomids are more phylogenetic similar in lakes with stocked fish relative to fishless lakes, in high elevation lakes in the Sierra Nevada. She used barcode data to generate her phylogeny of chironomids. If you have barcode data and want to search BOLD Systems site, one option is doing it from R using rbold, a package under development at <a href="http://ropensci.org/">rOpenSci</a> (code at <a href="https://github.com/sckott/rbold">Github</a>).</p>
<p>Jessica Gurevitch presented a large working group&rsquo;s methods/approach to a set of reviews on invasion biology. We didn&rsquo;t get to see a lot of results from this work, but I personally was glad to see her explaining to a packed room the utility of meta-analysis, and comparing to the medical field in which meta-analysis is sort of the gold standard by which to draw conclusions.</p>
<p>Following Jessica, Jason Fridley told us about the Evolutionary Imbalance Hypothesis (EIH) (see my notes <a href="http://schamber.wordpress.com/lab-notebook-2/">here</a>). He posed the problem of, when two biotas come together, what determines which species are retained in this new community and which species are left out. He listed a litany of traits/responses to measure to get at this problem, but suggested that with a little bit of &ldquo;desktop ecology&rdquo;, we could simply ask: Is the invasability of X region related to the phylogenetic diversity of that region? In three destination regions (Eastern Deciduous Forests, Mediterranean California, and the Czech Republic) out of four there was a positive relationship between proportion of invasive plant species in a source region and the phylogenetic diversity of the source regions.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wednesday at #ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/wednesday-at-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2011 08:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/wednesday-at-esa11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interesting talks/posters:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ethan White&amp;rsquo;s poster describing &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecologicaldata.org/&#34;&gt;EcologicalData.org&lt;/a&gt; was of course awesome given my interest in getting data into the hands of ecologists over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://ropensci.org/&#34;&gt;rOpenSci.org&lt;/a&gt;. Ethan also has software you can download on your machine to get the datasets you want easily - &lt;a href=&#34;http://ecologicaldata.org/ecodata-retriever&#34;&gt;EcoData Retriever&lt;/a&gt;. [rOpenSci will try to take advantage of their work and allow you to call the retriever from R]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carl Boettiger&amp;rsquo;s talk was awesome. He explained how we need better tools to be able to predict collapses using early warning signals. He developed a way to estimate the statistical distribution of probabilities of system collapse. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jennifer Dunne: Explained how she put together an ancient network from Germany. Bravo. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carlos Melian explained his model of network buildup that starts from individuals, allows speciation, and other evolutionary processes. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rachel Winfree told us that in two sets of mutualistic plant-pollinator networks in New Jersey and California, that the least connected pollinator species were the most likely to be lost from the network with increasing agricultural intensity. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dan Cariveau suggests that pollination crop services can be stabilized even with increasing agriculture intensity if in fact pollinator species respond in different ways. That is, some pollinators may decrease in abundance with increasing ag intensity, while other species may increase - retaining overall pollination services to crops.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Interesting talks/posters:</p>
<ul>
<li>Ethan White&rsquo;s poster describing <a href="http://ecologicaldata.org/">EcologicalData.org</a> was of course awesome given my interest in getting data into the hands of ecologists over at <a href="http://ropensci.org/">rOpenSci.org</a>. Ethan also has software you can download on your machine to get the datasets you want easily - <a href="http://ecologicaldata.org/ecodata-retriever">EcoData Retriever</a>. [rOpenSci will try to take advantage of their work and allow you to call the retriever from R]</li>
<li>Carl Boettiger&rsquo;s talk was awesome. He explained how we need better tools to be able to predict collapses using early warning signals. He developed a way to estimate the statistical distribution of probabilities of system collapse. </li>
<li>Jennifer Dunne: Explained how she put together an ancient network from Germany. Bravo. </li>
<li>Carlos Melian explained his model of network buildup that starts from individuals, allows speciation, and other evolutionary processes. </li>
<li>Rachel Winfree told us that in two sets of mutualistic plant-pollinator networks in New Jersey and California, that the least connected pollinator species were the most likely to be lost from the network with increasing agricultural intensity. </li>
<li>Dan Cariveau suggests that pollination crop services can be stabilized even with increasing agriculture intensity if in fact pollinator species respond in different ways. That is, some pollinators may decrease in abundance with increasing ag intensity, while other species may increase - retaining overall pollination services to crops.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monday at ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/monday-at-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2011 22:17:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/monday-at-esa11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Monday was a good day at ESA in Austin. There were a few topics I promised to report on in my blogging/tweeting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;focused on open source data. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nceas.ucsb.edu/~strasser/Site/Home.html&#34;&gt;Carly Strasser&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; presentation on guidelines for data management was awesome (including other talks in the symposium on Creating Effective Data Management Plans for Ecological Research). Although this was a good session, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but wish that they had hammered home the need for open science more. Oh well. Also, they talked a lot about how, and not a lot of why we should properly curate data. Still, a good session. One issue Carly and I talked about was tracking code in versioning systems such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;. There doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be a culture of versioning code for analyses/simulations in ecology. But when we get there&amp;hellip;it will be easier to share/track/collaborate on  code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Monday was a good day at ESA in Austin. There were a few topics I promised to report on in my blogging/tweeting.</p>
<p>&hellip;focused on open source data. <a href="http://www.nceas.ucsb.edu/~strasser/Site/Home.html">Carly Strasser&rsquo;s</a> presentation on guidelines for data management was awesome (including other talks in the symposium on Creating Effective Data Management Plans for Ecological Research). Although this was a good session, I can&rsquo;t help but wish that they had hammered home the need for open science more. Oh well. Also, they talked a lot about how, and not a lot of why we should properly curate data. Still, a good session. One issue Carly and I talked about was tracking code in versioning systems such as <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>. There doesn&rsquo;t seem to be a culture of versioning code for analyses/simulations in ecology. But when we get there&hellip;it will be easier to share/track/collaborate on  code.</p>
<p>&hellip;used R software. <a href="http://eco.confex.com/eco/2011/preliminaryprogram/abstract_31982.htm">David Jennings</a> talked about a meta-analysis asking if phylogenetic distance influences competition strength in pairwise experiments. David used the metafor package in R to do his meta-analysis. Good form sir.</p>
<p>&hellip;did cool science. <a href="http://www.ecologicalevolution.org/people/former-lab-members/matthew-helmus/">Matt Helmus</a> presented a great talk on phylogenetic species area curves (likely using R, or Matlab maybe?).</p>
<p>p.s. <a href="http://ropensci.org/developers/">We</a> launched <a href="http://ropensci.org/2011/07/welcome-to-ropensci/">rOpenSci</a> today.</p>
<p>Oddities:</p>
<ul>
<li>The Tilman effect - Tilman&rsquo;s talk was so packed it looked like there was a line waiting to get into a trendy bar. <a href="http://www.math.ualberta.ca/~ashander/images/til.jpg">Here&rsquo;s a picture</a> (credit: Jaime Ashander). Bigger room next time anyone? </li>
<li>Wiley came out with an open source journal called <a href="http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/journal/10.1002/(ISSN)2045-7758">Ecology and Evolution</a>. This brings them to 3 open source journals (the other two are in other fields). We (<a href="http://ropensci.org/">rOpenSci</a>) will attempt to hand-shake with these journals. </li>
<li>The vegetarian lunch option was surprisingly good. Nice.</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blogging/tweeting from ESA11</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/bloggingtweeting-from-esa11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2011 14:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/bloggingtweeting-from-esa11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be blogging about the upcoming Ecological Society of America meeting in Austin, TX. I will focus on discussing talks/posters that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have taken a cool approach to using data, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have focused on open science/data, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Done something cool with R software, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Are just exciting in general&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will also tweet throughout the meeting from @recology_ (yes the underscore is part of the name, recology was already taken). &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I will be blogging about the upcoming Ecological Society of America meeting in Austin, TX. I will focus on discussing talks/posters that:</p>
<ol>
<li>Have taken a cool approach to using data, or</li>
<li>Have focused on open science/data, or</li>
<li>Done something cool with R software, or</li>
<li>Are just exciting in general</li>
</ol>
<p>I will also tweet throughout the meeting from @recology_ (yes the underscore is part of the name, recology was already taken). </p>
<p>The hashtag for the meeting this year is #ESA11</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Models in Evolutionary Ecology seminar, organized by Timothee Poisot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/models-in-evolutionary-ecology-seminar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2011 07:27:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/07/models-in-evolutionary-ecology-seminar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is one of the talks by Thomas Brouquet, and see the rest &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;here&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;iframe frameborder=&#34;0&#34; height=&#34;270&#34; src=&#34;http://www.dailymotion.com/embed/video/xjylea&#34; width=&#34;480&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dailymotion.com/video/xjylea_thomas-broquet_tech&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Thomas Broquet&lt;/a&gt; &lt;i&gt;by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dailymotion.com/mez_en_video&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;mez_en_video&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Here is one of the talks by Thomas Brouquet, and see the rest <!-- raw HTML omitted -->here<!-- raw HTML omitted -->.</p>


<iframe frameborder="0" height="270" src="http://www.dailymotion.com/embed/video/xjylea" width="480"></iframe><br />

<a href="http://www.dailymotion.com/video/xjylea_thomas-broquet_tech" target="_blank">Thomas Broquet</a> <i>by <a href="http://www.dailymotion.com/mez_en_video" target="_blank">mez_en_video</a></i>


]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iEvoBio 2011 Synopsis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We just wrapped up the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;2011 iEvoBio meeting&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. It was awesome! If you didn&amp;rsquo;t go this year or last year, definitely think about going next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of the cool projects that were discussed at the meeting (apologies if I left some out):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Vistrails&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: workflow tool, awesome project by Claudio Silva&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Commplish&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: purpose is to use via API&amp;rsquo;s, not with the web UI&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Phylopic&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: a database of life-form silouhettes, including an API for remote access, sweet!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Gloome&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;MappingLife&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: awesome geographic/etc data visualization interace on the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;SuiteSMA&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: visualizating multiple alignments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;treeBASE&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: R interface to treebase, by &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Carl Boettiger&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;VertNet&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: database for vertebrate natural history collections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;RevBayes&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: revamp of MrBayes, with GUI, etc. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Phenoscape Knowledge Base&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Peter Midford lightning talk: talked about matching taxonomic and genetic data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;BiSciCol&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: biological science collections tracker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Ontogrator&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;TNRS&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: taxonomic name resolution service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Barcode of Life data systems&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;remote access&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Moorea Biocode Project&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Microbial LTER&amp;rsquo;s data&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;BirdVis&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: interactive bird data visualization (Claudio Silva in collaboration with Cornell Lab of Ornithology)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Crowdlabs&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: I think the site is down right now, another project by Claudio Silva&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Phycas&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;: Bayesian phylogenetics, can you just call this from R?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RIP MrBayes!!!! replaced by RevBayes (see 9 above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Slides of presentations will be at &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;Slideshare&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; (not all presentations up yet)          &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A birds of a feather group I was involved in proposed an idea (TOL-o-matic) like Phylomatic, but of broader scope, for easy access and submission of trees, and perhaps even social (think just pushing a &amp;lsquo;SHARE&amp;rsquo; button within PAUP, RevBayes, or other phylogenetics software)! &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Synopses of Birds of a Feather discussion groups: &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://piratepad.net/iEvoBio11-BoF-reportouts&#34;&gt;http://piratepad.net/iEvoBio11-BoF-reportouts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We just wrapped up the <!-- raw HTML omitted -->2011 iEvoBio meeting<!-- raw HTML omitted -->. It was awesome! If you didn&rsquo;t go this year or last year, definitely think about going next year.</p>
<p>Here is a list of the cool projects that were discussed at the meeting (apologies if I left some out):</p>
<ul>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Vistrails<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: workflow tool, awesome project by Claudio Silva</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Commplish<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: purpose is to use via API&rsquo;s, not with the web UI</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Phylopic<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: a database of life-form silouhettes, including an API for remote access, sweet!</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Gloome<!-- raw HTML omitted --></li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->MappingLife<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: awesome geographic/etc data visualization interace on the web</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->SuiteSMA<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: visualizating multiple alignments</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->treeBASE<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: R interface to treebase, by <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Carl Boettiger<!-- raw HTML omitted --></li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->VertNet<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: database for vertebrate natural history collections</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->RevBayes<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: revamp of MrBayes, with GUI, etc. </li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Phenoscape Knowledge Base<!-- raw HTML omitted --></li>
<li>Peter Midford lightning talk: talked about matching taxonomic and genetic data</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->BiSciCol<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: biological science collections tracker</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Ontogrator<!-- raw HTML omitted --> </li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->TNRS<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: taxonomic name resolution service</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Barcode of Life data systems<!-- raw HTML omitted -->, and <!-- raw HTML omitted -->remote access<!-- raw HTML omitted --></li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Moorea Biocode Project<!-- raw HTML omitted --></li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Microbial LTER&rsquo;s data<!-- raw HTML omitted --></li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->BirdVis<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: interactive bird data visualization (Claudio Silva in collaboration with Cornell Lab of Ornithology)</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Crowdlabs<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: I think the site is down right now, another project by Claudio Silva</li>
<li><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Phycas<!-- raw HTML omitted -->: Bayesian phylogenetics, can you just call this from R?</li>
<li>RIP MrBayes!!!! replaced by RevBayes (see 9 above)</li>
<li>Slides of presentations will be at <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Slideshare<!-- raw HTML omitted --> (not all presentations up yet)          </li>
<li>A birds of a feather group I was involved in proposed an idea (TOL-o-matic) like Phylomatic, but of broader scope, for easy access and submission of trees, and perhaps even social (think just pushing a &lsquo;SHARE&rsquo; button within PAUP, RevBayes, or other phylogenetics software)! </li>
<li>Synopses of Birds of a Feather discussion groups: <!-- raw HTML omitted --><a href="http://piratepad.net/iEvoBio11-BoF-reportouts">http://piratepad.net/iEvoBio11-BoF-reportouts</a><!-- raw HTML omitted --></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
