<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Phylogenetics on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/phylogenetics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Phylogenetics on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/phylogenetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Function for phylogeny resolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/01/phylogeny-resolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/01/phylogeny-resolution/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Yeah, so the treeresstats function had a problem in one of the calculations. I fixed that and added some more calulcations to the function.
I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find any functions to calculate number of polytomies, and related metrics.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a simple function that gives four metrics on a phylo tree object:
# calculate tree resolution stats treeresstats &amp;lt;- function(x) { require(phangorn) # load the phangorn package todo &amp;lt;- ( 1+Ntip(x)) : (Ntip(x) + Nnode(x) ) trsize_tips &amp;lt;- Ntip(x) trsize_nodes &amp;lt;- Nnode(x) polytomyvec &amp;lt;- sapply(todo, function(y) length(Children(x, y))) numpolys &amp;lt;- length(polytomyvec[polytomyvec &amp;gt; 2]) numpolysbytrsize_tips &amp;lt;- numpolys/trsize_tips numpolysbytrsize_nodes &amp;lt;- numpolys/trsize_nodes proptipsdescpoly &amp;lt;- sum(polytomyvec[polytomyvec &amp;gt; 2])/trsize_tips propnodesdich &amp;lt;- length(polytomyvec[polytomyvec == 2])/trsize_nodes list(trsize_tips = trsize_tips, trsize_nodes = trsize_nodes, numpolys = numpolys, numpolysbytrsize_tips = numpolysbytrsize_tips, numpolysbytrsize_nodes = numpolysbytrsize_nodes, proptipsdescpoly = proptipsdescpoly, propnodesdich = propnodesdich) } # Single tree example tree &amp;lt;- read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My talk on doing phylogenetics in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/my-talk-on-doing-phylogenetics-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2011 13:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/11/my-talk-on-doing-phylogenetics-in-r/</guid>
      <description>I gave a talk today on doing very basic phylogenetics in R, including getting sequence data, aligning sequence data, plotting trees, doing trait evolution stuff, etc.
Please comment if you have code for doing bayesian phylogenetic inference in R. I know phyloch has function mrbayes, but can&amp;rsquo;t get it to work&amp;hellip;
Phylogenetics in R View more presentations from schamber </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jonathan Eisen on the Fourth Domain and Open Science</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/jonathan-eisen-on-fourth-domain-and/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2011 18:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/jonathan-eisen-on-fourth-domain-and/</guid>
      <description> Stalking the Fourth Domain with Jonathan Eisen, Ph D from mendelspod on Vimeo. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenure track position in systematics at the University of Vermont</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/tenure-track-position-in-systematics-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 15:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/tenure-track-position-in-systematics-at/</guid>
      <description>There is an awesome position opening up for an assistant professor in systematics at the University of Vermont. Below is the announcement, and see the original post at the Distributed Ecology blog. Why is this related to R? One can do a lot of systematics work in R, including retrieving scientific collections data through an upcoming package handshaking with VertNet (part of the rOpenSci project), managing large data sets, retrieval of GenBank data through the ape package (see fxn read.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iEvoBio 2011 Synopsis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>We just wrapped up the 2011 iEvoBio meeting. It was awesome! If you didn&amp;rsquo;t go this year or last year, definitely think about going next year.
Here is a list of the cool projects that were discussed at the meeting (apologies if I left some out):
Vistrails: workflow tool, awesome project by Claudio Silva Commplish: purpose is to use via API&amp;rsquo;s, not with the web UI Phylopic: a database of life-form silouhettes, including an API for remote access, sweet!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>searching ITIS and fetching Phylomatic trees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/searching-itis-and-fetching-phylomatic-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2011 17:35:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/searching-itis-and-fetching-phylomatic-trees/</guid>
      <description>I am writing a set of functions to search ITIS for taxonomic information (more databases to come) and functions to fetch plant phylogenetic trees from Phylomatic. Code at github.
Also, see the examples in the demos folder on the Github site above.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>phylogenetic signal simulations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/phylogenetic-signal-simulations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2011 08:13:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/phylogenetic-signal-simulations/</guid>
      <description>I did a little simulation to examine how K and lambda vary in response to tree size (and how they compare to each other on the same simulated trees). I use Liam Revell&amp;rsquo;s functions fastBM to generate traits, and phylosig to measure phylogenetic signal.
Two observations:
First, it seems that lambda is more sensitive than K to tree size, but then lambda levels out at about 40 species, whereas K continues to vary around a mean of 1.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A simple function for plotting phylogenies in ggplot2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/simple-function-for-plotting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2011 14:37:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/simple-function-for-plotting/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Greg jordan has a much more elegant way of plotting trees with ggplot2. See his links in the comments below.
I wrote a simple function for plotting a phylogeny in ggplot2. However, it only handles a 3 species tree right now, as I haven&amp;rsquo;t figured out how to generalize the approach to N species. It&amp;rsquo;s at https://gist.github.com/977207
Any ideas on how to improve this?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of functions for comparative phylogenetics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/comparison-of-functions-for-comparative-phylogenetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 10:08:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/comparison-of-functions-for-comparative-phylogenetics/</guid>
      <description>With all the packages (and beta stage groups of functions) for comparative phylogenetics in R (tested here: picante, geiger, ape, motmot, Liam Revell&amp;rsquo;s functions), I was simply interested in which functions to use in cases where multiple functions exist to do the same thing. I only show default settings, so perhaps these functions would differ under different parameter settings. [I am using a Mac 2.4 GHz i5, 4GB RAM]
Get motmot here: https://r-forge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treebase trees from R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/treebase-trees-from-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2011 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/treebase-trees-from-r/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: See Carl Boettiger&amp;rsquo;s functions/package at Github for searching Treebase here.
Treebase is a great resource for phylogenetic trees, and has a nice interface for searching for certain types of trees. However, if you want to simply download a lot of trees for analyses (like that in Davies et al.), then you want to be able to access trees in bulk (I believe Treebase folks are working on an API though).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
