<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Government on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/government/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Government on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/government/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>rsunlight - R client for Sunlight Labs APIs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2014/08/rsunlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2014/08/rsunlight/</guid>
      <description>My last blog post on this package was so long ago the package wrapped both New York Times APIs and Sunlight Labs APIs and the package was called govdat. I split that package up into rsunlight for Sunlight Labs APIs and rtimes for some New York Times APIs. rtimes is in development at Github.
We&amp;rsquo;ve updated the package to include four sets of functions, one set for each of four Sunlight Labs APIs (with a separate prefix for each API):</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>govdat - SunlightLabs and New York Times Congress data via R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/govdat-vignette/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/govdat-vignette/</guid>
      <description>I started an R package a while back, and a few people have shown interest, so I thought it was time to revist the code. govdat is an interface to various APIs for government data: currently the Sunlight Labs APIs, and the New York Times congress API. Returned objects from functions are simple lists. In future versions of govdat, I may change how data is returned. The following are examples (which is also the package vignette) of using the Sunlight Labs API.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting data on your government</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/gov-dat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2012/09/gov-dat/</guid>
      <description>I created an R package a while back to interact with some APIs that serve up data on what our elected represenatives are up to, including the New York Times Congress API, and the Sunlight Labs API.
What kinds of things can you do with govdat? Here are a few examples.
How do the two major parties differ in the use of certain words (searches the congressional record using the Sunlight Labs Capitol Words API)?</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
