<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Jobs on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/jobs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jobs on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.144.2</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/jobs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Job searching notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/10/job-searching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/10/job-searching/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;notes to self for next job hunt (some of which may be generally useful):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t apply to general tech companies anymore for many reasons.
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;heard back from very very few but that may be b/c I don&amp;rsquo;t know many people at general tech companies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;never been able to get through interviews; they&amp;rsquo;re presumably looking for computer science grads (not me)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;most of their missions are probably not stuff I&amp;rsquo;d be happy about at the end of the day. despite missions of doing xyz, it&amp;rsquo;s probably really about $$&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t apply to pharma companies any more. there&amp;rsquo;s lots of good software jobs in that sector, but i&amp;rsquo;ve struck out 3 times, and so that&amp;rsquo;s a clear pattern my background/whatever isn&amp;rsquo;t something they want&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;next time only apply where I have a connection that can refer me or dig around for a referral. it&amp;rsquo;s super easy to apply for jobs, especially if you don&amp;rsquo;t write a cover letter; however, the less time I spend surely the less likely I am to hear back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;make sure (and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably fail to do it again this time, ugh) to write down what questions I was asked, how I answered, and how to improve on that answer. then study and reference those questions and answers for the next interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its good to have multiple offers at the same time, but then deciding is harder - &amp;amp; I don&amp;rsquo;t love to negotiating - so maybe don&amp;rsquo;t worry about multiple offers at the same time next time around&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have relatively low expectations in any interview b/c I don&amp;rsquo;t do technical interviews well - I also try to seek out orgs that do not have crazy technical interview processes - eg., Roche had a whiteboard technical interview that I totally bombed, but was unsurprising in hindsight since the interviewer was an ex-Googler. I&amp;rsquo;m more of a thinker than a quick responder, making it hard to do well in very fast paced (for me) tech interviews. Though I know i have been a good software engineer where I&amp;rsquo;ve worked, so these fast paced tech interviews are probably selecting for a certain kind of brain function I guess?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;seek out orgs with interview processes that have take home assignments - or at least timed coding tests on something like hackerrank - instead of live whiteboard/zoom tech inteviews
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my last job Deck had a take home test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.axiomdatascience.com/&#34;&gt;Axiom DS&lt;/a&gt; has a take home test approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://adhoc.team/&#34;&gt;AdHoc&lt;/a&gt; uses a take home test approach&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invitae had a hackerrank test, not a take home but better than live coding test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;cover letters? I still don&amp;rsquo;t know whether these are worth doing or not. the advice seems to be mixed. they sure take a lot of time, so I hope they&amp;rsquo;re not necessary for most hiring managers; given my bullet above about spending more time on fewer applications, I could find time for a cover letter on every application if ther&amp;rsquo;s not that many&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;some data about this last job search:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>notes to self for next job hunt (some of which may be generally useful):</p>
<ul>
<li>don&rsquo;t apply to general tech companies anymore for many reasons.
<ol>
<li>heard back from very very few but that may be b/c I don&rsquo;t know many people at general tech companies</li>
<li>never been able to get through interviews; they&rsquo;re presumably looking for computer science grads (not me)</li>
<li>most of their missions are probably not stuff I&rsquo;d be happy about at the end of the day. despite missions of doing xyz, it&rsquo;s probably really about $$</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>don&rsquo;t apply to pharma companies any more. there&rsquo;s lots of good software jobs in that sector, but i&rsquo;ve struck out 3 times, and so that&rsquo;s a clear pattern my background/whatever isn&rsquo;t something they want</li>
<li>next time only apply where I have a connection that can refer me or dig around for a referral. it&rsquo;s super easy to apply for jobs, especially if you don&rsquo;t write a cover letter; however, the less time I spend surely the less likely I am to hear back</li>
<li>make sure (and I&rsquo;ll probably fail to do it again this time, ugh) to write down what questions I was asked, how I answered, and how to improve on that answer. then study and reference those questions and answers for the next interview</li>
<li>its good to have multiple offers at the same time, but then deciding is harder - &amp; I don&rsquo;t love to negotiating - so maybe don&rsquo;t worry about multiple offers at the same time next time around</li>
<li>I have relatively low expectations in any interview b/c I don&rsquo;t do technical interviews well - I also try to seek out orgs that do not have crazy technical interview processes - eg., Roche had a whiteboard technical interview that I totally bombed, but was unsurprising in hindsight since the interviewer was an ex-Googler. I&rsquo;m more of a thinker than a quick responder, making it hard to do well in very fast paced (for me) tech interviews. Though I know i have been a good software engineer where I&rsquo;ve worked, so these fast paced tech interviews are probably selecting for a certain kind of brain function I guess?</li>
<li>seek out orgs with interview processes that have take home assignments - or at least timed coding tests on something like hackerrank - instead of live whiteboard/zoom tech inteviews
<ul>
<li>my last job Deck had a take home test</li>
<li><a href="https://www.axiomdatascience.com/">Axiom DS</a> has a take home test approach</li>
<li><a href="https://adhoc.team/">AdHoc</a> uses a take home test approach</li>
<li>Invitae had a hackerrank test, not a take home but better than live coding test</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>cover letters? I still don&rsquo;t know whether these are worth doing or not. the advice seems to be mixed. they sure take a lot of time, so I hope they&rsquo;re not necessary for most hiring managers; given my bullet above about spending more time on fewer applications, I could find time for a cover letter on every application if ther&rsquo;s not that many</li>
</ul>
<p>some data about this last job search:</p>
<ul>
<li>48: orgs that took time to say No</li>
<li>51: orgs that didn&rsquo;t respond</li>
<li>10: orgs that interviewed me (including recruiter only)</li>
<li>1: thanks hutch!</li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tenure track position in systematics at the University of Vermont</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/tenure-track-position-in-systematics-at/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 15:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/08/tenure-track-position-in-systematics-at/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an awesome position opening up for an assistant professor in systematics at the University of Vermont. Below is the announcement, and see the &lt;a href=&#34;http://currentecology.blogspot.com/2011/08/tenure-track-position-in-systematics-at.html&#34;&gt;original post&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://currentecology.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Distributed Ecology blog&lt;/a&gt;. Why is this related to R? One can do a lot of systematics work in R, including retrieving scientific collections data through an upcoming package handshaking with &lt;a href=&#34;http://vertnet.org/index.php&#34;&gt;VertNet&lt;/a&gt; (part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ropensci.org/&#34;&gt;rOpenSci&lt;/a&gt; project), managing large data sets, retrieval of GenBank data through the ape package (see fxn read.genbank), phylogenetic reconstruction and analysis, and more. So I am sure a systematist with R ninja skills will surely have a head up on the rest of the field.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>There is an awesome position opening up for an assistant professor in systematics at the University of Vermont. Below is the announcement, and see the <a href="http://currentecology.blogspot.com/2011/08/tenure-track-position-in-systematics-at.html">original post</a> at the <a href="http://currentecology.blogspot.com/">Distributed Ecology blog</a>. Why is this related to R? One can do a lot of systematics work in R, including retrieving scientific collections data through an upcoming package handshaking with <a href="http://vertnet.org/index.php">VertNet</a> (part of the <a href="http://ropensci.org/">rOpenSci</a> project), managing large data sets, retrieval of GenBank data through the ape package (see fxn read.genbank), phylogenetic reconstruction and analysis, and more. So I am sure a systematist with R ninja skills will surely have a head up on the rest of the field.</p>
<p><strong>Assistant Professor in Systematics</strong></p>
<p>Department of Biology<br>
University of Vermont<br>
Burlington, Vermont</p>
<p>The Department of Biology of the University of Vermont seeks applications for a tenure- track Assistant Professor position in Systematics and Evolutionary Biology of arthropods, especially insects. The position will be open in the fall of 2012. The successful candidate will have expertise in classical and molecular systematics, including analysis of complex data sets. Candidates pursuing phylogenomics and innovative methods in bioinformatics in combination with taxonomy are especially encouraged to apply. Department information at: <a href="http://www.uvm.edu/~biology/">http://www.uvm.edu/~biology/</a>.</p>
<p>All applicants are expected to: 1) hold a Ph.D. degree in relevant disciplines and have two or more years of postdoctoral experience; 2) develop a competitively funded research program; 3) teach undergraduate courses (chosen from among general biology, evolution, systematic entomology, and others in the candidate&rsquo;s expertise); 4) teach, mentor and advise undergraduate and graduate students; and 5) oversee a natural history collection of historic significance.</p>
<p>Candidates must apply online: <a href="http://www.uvmjobs.com/">http://www.uvmjobs.com/</a>. On left see &ldquo;Search Postings&rdquo; then find &ldquo;Biology&rdquo; under &ldquo;HCM Department&rdquo; then posting 0040090 (first posting). Sorry, but we cannot supply the direct link because it will time out.</p>
<p>Attach a cover letter with a statement of research focus and teaching interests (one document), a curriculum vitae, representative publications, and the contact information of three references.</p>
<p>Review of applications will begin on September 15, 2011, and will continue until the position is filled. Questions and up to three additional publications may be directed to Dr. Jos. J. Schall: <a href="mailto:jschall@uvm.edu">jschall@uvm.edu</a>.</p>
<p>The University of Vermont recently identified several &ldquo;Spires of Excellence&rdquo; in which it will strategically focus institutional investments and growth over the next several years. One spire associated with the position is Complex Systems. Candidates whose research interests align with this spire are especially encouraged to apply<a href="http://www.uvm.edu/~tri/">http://www.uvm.edu/~tri/</a>.<br>
The University seeks faculty who can contribute to the diversity and excellence of the academic community through their research, teaching, and/or service. Applicants are requested to include in their cover letter information about how they will further this goal. The University of Vermont is an Affirmative Action/Equal Opportunity employer. The Department is committed to increasing faculty diversity and welcomes applications from women, underrepresented ethnic, racial and cultural groups, and from people with disabilities.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
