<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Methods on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/methods/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Methods on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 13:03:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/methods/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My take on an R introduction talk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/my-take-on-r-introduction-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2011 13:03:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/09/my-take-on-r-introduction-talk/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: I put in an R tutorial as a Github gist below.
Here is a short intro R talk I gave today&amp;hellip;for what it&amp;rsquo;s worth&amp;hellip;
R Introduction View more presentations from schamber Here&amp;rsquo;s the tutorial in a GitHub gist: https://gist.github.com/1208321</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iEvoBio 2011 Synopsis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 21:38:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/ievobio-2011-synopsis/</guid>
      <description>We just wrapped up the 2011 iEvoBio meeting. It was awesome! If you didn&amp;rsquo;t go this year or last year, definitely think about going next year.
Here is a list of the cool projects that were discussed at the meeting (apologies if I left some out):
Vistrails: workflow tool, awesome project by Claudio Silva Commplish: purpose is to use via API&amp;rsquo;s, not with the web UI Phylopic: a database of life-form silouhettes, including an API for remote access, sweet!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to fit power laws</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/how-to-fit-power-laws/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2011 15:24:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/06/how-to-fit-power-laws/</guid>
      <description>A new paper out in Ecology by Xiao and colleagues (in press, here) compares the use of log-transformation to non-linear regression for analyzing power-laws.
They suggest that the error distribution should determine which method performs better. When your errors are additive, homoscedastic, and normally distributed, they propose using non-linear regression. When errors are multiplicative, heteroscedastic, and lognormally distributed, they suggest using linear regression on log-transformed data. The assumptions about these two methods are different, so cannot be correct for a single dataset.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RHIPE package in R for interfacing between Hadoop and R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/rhipe-package-in-r-for-interfacing-between-hadoop-and-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2011 19:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/05/rhipe-package-in-r-for-interfacing-between-hadoop-and-r/</guid>
      <description>RHIPE: An Interface Between Hadoop and R
Presented by Saptarshi Guha
And this review of methods for interfacing with Hadoop suggests R&amp;rsquo;s RHIPE is quite nice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phylometa from R: Randomization via Tip Shuffle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/phylometa-from-r-randomization-via-tip-shuffle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 13:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/phylometa-from-r-randomization-via-tip-shuffle/</guid>
      <description>&amp;mdash;UPDATE: I am now using code formatting from gist.github, so I replaced the old prettyR code (sorry guys). The github way is much easier and prettier. I hope readers like the change.
I wrote earlier about some code I wrote for running Phylometa (software to do phylogenetic meta-analysis) from R.
I have been concerned about what exactly is the right penalty for including phylogeny in a meta-analysis. E.g.: AIC is calculated from Q in Phylometa, and Q increases with tree size.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjust branch lengths with node ages: comparison of two methods</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/adjust-branch-lengths-with-node-ages-comparison-of-two-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Apr 2011 13:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/04/adjust-branch-lengths-with-node-ages-comparison-of-two-methods/</guid>
      <description>Here is an approach for comparing two methods of adjusting branch lengths on trees: bladj in the program Phylocom and a fxn written by Gene Hunt at the Smithsonian.
Get the code and example files (tree and node ages) at https://gist.github.com/938313
Get phylocom at http://www.phylodiversity.net/phylocom/
Gene Hunt&amp;rsquo;s method has many options you can mess with, including setting tip ages (not available in bladj), setting node ages, and minimum branch length imposed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>cloudnumbers.com</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/03/cloudnumbers-com/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 07:28:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/03/cloudnumbers-com/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: I guess it still is not actually available. Bummer&amp;hellip;
Has anyone used cloudnumbers.com?
http://www.cloudnumbers.com/
They provide cloud computing, and have built in applications, including R.
How well does it work? Does it increase processing speed? I guess it may at the least free up RAM and processor space on your own machine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five ways to visualize your pairwise comparisons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/03/for-all-your-pairwise-comparison-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2011 12:49:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/03/for-all-your-pairwise-comparison-needs/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: At the bottom are two additional methods, and some additions (underlined) are added to the original 5 methods. Thanks for all the feedback&amp;hellip;
-Also, another post here about ordered-categorical data-Also #2, a method combining splom and hexbin packages here, for larger datasets
In data analysis it is often nice to look at all pairwise combinations of continuous variables in scatterplots. Up until recently, I have used the function splom in the package lattice, but ggplot2 has superior aesthetics, I think anyway.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phenotypic selection analysis in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2011/02/phenotypic-selection-analysis-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2011 09:43:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2011/02/phenotypic-selection-analysis-in-r/</guid>
      <description>I have up to recently always done my phenotypic selection analyses in SAS. I finally got some code I think works to do everything SAS would do. Feedback much appreciated!
########################Selection analyses############################# install.packages(c(&amp;#34;car&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;reshape&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;ggplot2&amp;#34;)) require(car) require(reshape) require(ggplot2) # Create data set dat &amp;lt;- data.frame(plant = seq(1,100,1), trait1 = rep(c(0.1,0.15,0.2,0.21,0.25,0.3,0.5,0.6,0.8,0.9,1,3,4,10,11,12,13,14,15,16), each = 5), trait2 = runif(100), fitness = rep(c(1,5,10,20,50), each = 20)) # Make relative fitness column dat_ &amp;lt;- cbind(dat, dat$fitness/mean(dat$fitness)) names(dat_)[5] &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;relfitness&amp;#34; # Standardize traits dat_ &amp;lt;- cbind(dat_[,-c(2:3)], rescaler(dat_[,c(2:3)],&amp;#34;sd&amp;#34;)) ####Selection differentials and correlations among traits, cor.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
