<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate Change on Recology</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/climate-change/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Climate Change on Recology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Engaging the public on climate change through phenology data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/phenology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/phenology/</guid>
      <description>ScienceOnline Climate I recently attended ScienceOnline Climate, a conference in Washington, D.C. at AAAS offices. You may have heard of the ScienceOnline annual meeting in North Carolina - this was one of their topical meetings focused on Climate Change. Another one is coming up in October, ScienceOnline Oceans. Search Twitter for #scioClimate (or the entire list of hashtags here) for tweets from the conference.
One of the sessions I attended was focused on how to democratize climate change knowledge, moderated by a fellow from the Union of Concerned Scientists.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working with climate data from the web in R</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/sciordata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2013/08/sciordata/</guid>
      <description>I recently attended ScienceOnline Climate, a conference in Washington, D.C. at AAAS. You may have heard of the ScienceOnline annual meeting in North Carolina - this was one of their topical meetings focused on Climate Change. I moderated a session on working with data from the web in R, focusing on climate data. Search Twitter for #scioClimate for tweets from the conference, and #sciordata for tweets from the session I ran.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
